

# Lionel Farjon

## Senior Software Engineer

Software Engineer with a business background. 6+ years experience in developing, extending and maintaining Single Web Applications. Experienced in driving projects from concept to launch, breaking down features into stories with determined deadlines, while working with an agile team. Passionate about building digital products with a desire to apply my skills in order to tackle more complex problems.

📈 lfarj100@gmail.com

+34-633-28-45-89



Barcelona



in linkedin.com/in/lionel-farjon

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, HTML5, CSS, SCSS, SASS, LESS

**Technologies** Angular 2, RxJS, NgRx, GraphQL, RestAPI, Node.js, Express.js, Firebase, GCP, AWS, Git, Github, GitLab, Jira,

Tailwind CSS, Angular Material, Stripe.is

Working knowledge React, Next.js, Ionic

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## Senior Frontend Engineer

The Mill Adventure

06/2022 - Present Malta (Remote)

Achievements/Tasks

- Develop and extend frontend components using Typescript, Angular 11 14, RxJS, Angular Material, GraphQL API (Apollo), Headless CMS (TakeShape and Hygraph - Graph CMS) and SCSS.
- Retrieve data from internal and external APIs, create data models inside Headless CMS to be consumed via GraphQL.
- Unit testing, e2e tests and build pipeline integration, committing merge requests (pull requests) using git version control (GitLab).
- Work inside a two week Scrum sprint, participate in daily stand-ups, team planning and code reviews.
- Implement and deliver new features as requested by customers inside Jira.

#### **Angular Developer**

#### LastOffr.com

10/2020 - Present Remote (Montreal, Canada)

Mission

- Lead product development and strategy. Conducted market research to assess competition and positioning.
- Identified customer needs to develop relevant product features rapidly.
- Full-stack development using Angular 12, RxJs, Angular Material, Tailwind CSS, GCP and Firebase.
- · Database modelling for Cloud Firestore. Wrote Cloud Firestore security rules to control access to database. OAuth and JWT token implementation.
- Wrote Cloud Functions to keep logic secure and private, send push notifications, SMS and automated emails.

#### **Angular Developer**

#### OwnEasy.ca

09/2017 - 10/2020 Montreal

Prop-tech startup currently penetrating the Canadian property market.

- Work closely with the business owner to gather and understand the business and functional requirements.
- Lead product development and strategy. Conducted market research to assess competition and positioning.
- Full stack development using Angular 8, Angular Material, Node.js and GCP.
- Modelled Cloud Firestore database for optimal & real-time reads and writes. Wrote Firestore security rules to control access to documents and collections in database.
- Implemented reactive forms based & JWT authentication. Maintained Auth State information throughout the web transaction.

# **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

# **E-Commerce Entrepreneur** Self-employed

05/2011 - 09/2017 Montreal

Mission

- Conducted market research to identify niches. Large scale business development. Negotiation and contract closing with international distributors and retailers.
- Created, launched and maintained a variety of Single Page Applications using Angular 4+ and Firebase (since 2016).
- Created, launched and maintained a wide variety of e-commerce websites using WordPress, Shopify or OpenCart.
- Heavily customised the themes, adding new sections, template styles, widgets and functions using PHP, MySQL, Javascript and CSS3.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Commerce Telfer School of Management

2006 - 2010 University of Ottawa